[Music]
all right sup y'all it's your boy Rhino
Raider here on the solo episode now I
told myself this week that I was going
to take it easy I was going to do a
short episode but I'm looking at this
Dock and that is probably not going to
be the case um and the reason for that
is because one I'm a long-winded
guy but for two um we have a lot of
things we need to talk about for 2025
with critical thinking okay so first
we're going to hit you with a couple
announcements and then I'm going to give
you a template for uh how to evaluate
your last year in bug Bounty and how to
set some goals for 2025 uh but but first
let's get to those announcements Okay so
um critical thinking is going to launch
some cool [__] in 2025 particularly in
January okay so uh the first thing that
I wanted to mention is that we are going
to launch the critical thinking
full-time bug bounty hunters Guild okay
um and I'm not sure we're going to call
it that just yet we're still kind of
workshopping the idea but since I'm I'm
recording this earlier in December um I
haven't got it fully completely worked
out yet um but essentially what it's
going to be is a a place where you apply
as a full-time bug Bounty Hunter and if
you're accepted into the community um
which full-time bug bounty hunters will
or people that make over $100,000 in bug
Bounty parttime um then you'll be
granted access and uh you'll get access
to a bunch of perks uh a community a
sense of accountability that's a big one
right there um a lot of hackers have
expressed to me that they kind of miss
the reality of having co-workers and
having some sort of sense of
accountability for their work um so this
initiative is an attempt to fix that um
there's going to be a lot of other
pieces to it as well um we're going to
put the details up for that uh on the
website at ctbb doow for fulltime ctbb
doow so if you're interested in that go
ahead and check it out but I'm pretty
optimistic for it I think it'll be
really helpful um and I I kind of need
it myself because for me just kind of
sharing personally um looking at this
past year I've spent a lot of time doing
critical thinking related stuff and
other stuff I had a bunch of personal
stuff come up this year with becoming a
father a bunch of other things but um a
lot of my time got taken away from
hacking uh and I think I need that sense
of accountability uh that this group
will offer to make sure I'm staying on
track and actually uh living the life
that I want to live uh as a hacker so I
think that'll be really helpful for a
lot of people um yeah if you're
interested check it out cb. show okay
second thing that we're releasing in in
uh 2025 I'm really excited for this one
this is the critical research lab so I
was thinking back over all the critical
thinking episodes that we've had and I
was reflecting on the ones that I liked
the most and the ones that I liked the
most was when we were presenting
original or like very newly released
research very granularly um and it and
that just felt so good and felt so right
so I was like okay how can we do more of
that and the answer to that is to take
away Justin's profits again from
critical thinking and put that back into
a research lab so uh what we're going to
do is we're going to select a a set of
researchers um from the bugani community
and give them a stipend uh for doing
research is probably not going to be
anything huge but it's going to be what
we can do um and that stipend will
hopefully help them mentally shift a
little bit from like oh I got to do bug
Bounty or everything that I do in
hacking should be directly financially
related to okay I'm a researcher and I'm
going to try to do more research um and
then when they're ready to release that
research whether it be something small
or like a big presentation then we're
going to do that through the podcast and
through the blog so we've already got
some really big names that I'm really
excited about um that have signed up for
it I'm going to get everything signed
and we'll put it up on the website
that'll be at cp. show crl for critical
research lab um yeah very excited for
that I think some amazing content is
going to come out of that in 2025 um but
I guess we'll see Okay cool so now let's
get into the uh the content of this
episode what I wanted to talk about was
my personal strategy for um goals and a
personal inventory uh of types as Bug
Hunter uh looking at 2024 and then
making goals for 2025 so let's go ahead
and take a look at that well okay first
first I should go back we did an episode
episode 51 uh at the end of the year in
2023 um and uh I just wanted to look
back on that and kind of compare the
statistics across the board and uh sort
of do a check-in with how I did and I
probably should have done this quarterly
um this is something that I think the
full-time bug bounty hunters Guild will
will help with um but looking back I did
all right on my goals so let let me go
through the goals that I had for 2024 I
had uh I would like to do more research
and that is the one that I did not do
right on top of doing book Bounty and uh
critical thinking and everything uh my
time really did not get allocated to
research this year um which is
unfortunate but that is something that I
do want to change in 2025
um the next one on the list is
accomplish badass stuff inside work
hours that was what I had um and I think
I did a really good job of this this
year I as a full-time Hunter you know
it's really easy to be at your computer
constantly but this year I think I did a
particularly good job of working my
eight hours or six hours or 12 hours
whatever I have allotted in
intentionally doing that right um and
then walking away at the end of the day
um much better than in previous years
which I think is a big Improvement uh
quality of life for me and for my family
um I had hack more iot stuff or hardcore
source code review and uh I did not do
as much iot stuff as I would have liked
though I did do a little bit and I did
do hardcore source code review which was
awesome and generated one of my favorite
moments of hacking uh in 2024 so I'll
tell you a little bit about that in a
second um but that one is a check for
sure I did get that one done um and then
uh I had non-traditional automation so
in this one I was talking about JS
monitoring and source code monitoring um
I did get some personal tooling for that
in place but I did not utilize it to its
full extent so I give myself half credit
on that
one um and then lastly I had influence
tool Creation in the community um and I
think that is something that we
definitely were able to do this year let
me let me grab some water really
quick I think that was definitely
something that that uh Joel and I
accomplished this year um there were a
lot of tools that came out of ideas uh
that came from critical thinking um and
man I was so happy to see that because
some really awesome stuff has been put
out um just off the top of my head the
403 bypasser um the kaido the kaido
notes uh app that static flow built
which is just totally changed my
workflow um what else was there I know
there was a couple other ones I didn't
put them in the notes but they'll
probably come to me later I'm just
really excited about that possibility
and the be the possibility to be able to
share like concepts with the community
and then potentially have some build
those uh I think that'll be great um so
overall I'm I'm hitting at like what is
that like a three and a half out of five
for
2024 not the worst not the best um but I
think we can do better this year okay so
let's go look at uh sort of a personal
inventory of 2024 and then uh uh we'll
move into 2025 now um the template that
I'm about to use I will be sharing to
you all that will be on the blog so you
can go to ct. blog
and it should take you to the blog or
just go to the website and click the
blog button or hacker notes button um
and there should be a a template up
there for this personal bug Bounty
Hunter inventory that I'm doing and then
also a uh a like goals for 2025 how to
set those goals so just some questions
to ask you uh to ask yourself you know
some introspection to do uh and that
will hopefully help you identify what
kind of hacker you want to be in 2025 um
and be sort of honest with yourself
about what hacker you were in 2024
because to be honest I'm reading through
some of these questions I'm thinking
back and um and I think there's some
things that I I need to change so let's
get to that okay so 2024 bug Bounty
Hunter personal inventory first question
on the list that I had is what moments
or bugs were most fulfilling to you as a
Bug Hunter in 2024 and why um and the
reason I stuck this question at the
beginning is because I think it's a
little bit telling but go ahead and
answer this question in your brain first
before you uh read read any further okay
uh or listen any further so uh for me
the most fulfilling moment was when I
was working on a SQL injection with
chubs at a live hacking event and we
finally freaking popped the bug and we
saw the errors in the logs and we're
like yes the SQL context is being
escaped I remember sitting at at this
desk right here where I am right now and
just like slamming my hands on the desk
and being so excited um and then the
other one was sort of a tossup up but it
was a crypto bug it was a crypto bug
that I had banged my head up against the
wall for like eight hours without any
progress and I was just very stubbornly
refusing to give up on this bug and I
eventually I did give up on it and uh
moved on and the next day I was sitting
in my hot tub and I solved it and I came
back inside and I tried it and it worked
um and that moment when I solved it in
the hot tub and I was like no way what
if I did it like that then uh that was
the moment that hit me and and so the
follow-up question of these were these
the moments you found the bug or were
these the moments you got the Bounty
right and I think that this can be a
telling question for anybody who is
trying to decide whether you know what
kind of bug Hunter they are because I
think um there is a big pull to Bounties
in the bug boundy world right uh there's
a lot of emphasis attached on this but
at the end of the day um you know when
you're trying to identify whether the
Bounty or the bug is important to you
whether you're trying to decide whether
you're a a passion based hunter or a a
fin finance-based Hunter um I think this
can be a good question uh for you to ask
yourself and what moment was most fond
when you looked at the phone and you saw
whoa that 50k Bounty just came in or was
it the moment when you finally popped
the bug um so that's something to
reflect upon and and just to be clear um
no no shame I'm not dissing anybody
who's a more of a a finance-based hacker
right if you're just trying to make
money in bug Bounty that's great that's
fine it sets you up for an amazing
lifestyle really if you can do it
full-time um I love it uh it's totally
worth doing it for just the finances but
I think a lot of us especially at the
top level are doing it also for the
passion which I think is great um and
you can kind of tell where you're at on
that Spectrum a little bit by by looking
at this
question okay so the next question that
I had here was looking back on 2024 uh
bug bounding performance were you
satisfied with one the number of bugs
that you had so for me I had 126 bugs in
2024 uh and that I think is pretty good
considering uh the the year that I've
had and how little I've been able to
hack um and that is a 25% increase from
last year um so I'm pretty pleased with
that I think that's that's kind of where
I want to be it's like roughly it's only
roughly two or two or more bugs per week
um which is not as much as I I was
hoping for um and I think I can do
better than that in 2025 but um given
the the year I'm pretty pleased with it
personally
okay number two was am I satisfied with
the impact of bugs now this is where it
gets a little tricky guys so for me I
had seven crits in 2024 uh and there's a
couple days left so maybe we'll they'll
get some more I just popped one not too
long ago um and there were uh 45 highs
57 mediums and 18 lows okay and I'm
looking at this and I'm like that's a
[__] ton of highs and not a lot of crits
that is a very low amount of crits um so
what I'm thinking this year is I kind of
struggled to get from that high to crit
range um so I think that's probably one
of the things that I'm going to put in
my 2025 goals is I need to try to push a
little bit further on some of these
highs to see if I can remove any of the
inhibiting factors um or or anything
that's reducing that score uh from high
and try to get it to a crint um because
45 is is a lot of highs relative to my
actual amount of of bugs that I had um
so I think there's probably some room to
grow there
um what kind of bugs are you finding
that was the next the next uh piece like
am I satisfied with what kind of bugs
I'm finding um and for me that is mostly
idor um Access Control bugs
authentication bypasses xss and this
year actually a decent amount of crypto
bugs which I was kind of pleased with um
and and so I am kind of pleased with
that distribution I would definitely
like to see more rcees I think we only
had a handful of rcees in 2024 um and I
would like to see more uh uh ssrf I
really did not have a ton of ssfs in
2024 um and I think that that's a bug
class that often has a lot of impact in
modern day architectures um and it's
just not something that I was able to
exploit effectively uh in 2024 I I did
have a couple blind xsss I mean not
blind ssss excuse me uh as blind ssfs um
and and a couple uh full read ssfs but
um there there wasn't as many as I would
have expected uh given where I think the
industry at so that's a that's a thought
um was I satisfied with the scope that
I'm working on so for me that was almost
entirely web this year um and I am
pretty pleased with that um I definitely
would like to have done a little bit
more mobile this year I kind of like to
keep those skills sharp but um I did do
a bit of mobile uh for like a two we
Sprint but there wasn't a lot of bugs
that fell out of it this time the app
that I was looking at was just really
really locked down and I had some mobile
hackers that I really respect also take
a look at it and yeah I mean it was it
was tight um so I still kind of kept
those skills sharp but didn't land as
many bugs out of it unfortunately um I
did however do some Enterprise uh
software hacking this year which I
really really enjoyed um and I
definitely would like to do more of that
in the future um was I satisfied with
the quality of my reports uh now this
one I think is the one where I gave
myself the lowest marks um this
definitely need need some
work like getting some
water um yeah so I think for me the the
quality of my reports was really not as
good as it need needed to be um and I
think that that was because I often am
putting off report writing till the end
of the day when I'm tired and I'm just
trying to stay in that flow state so I
think I'm finding more bugs but the
report quality is worse so how do I fix
that one I think can sort of uh try to
make that process a little bit less
friction by using the um kaido Notes app
that static flow uh release that I
mentioned before um I think it'll be
really nice to start writing some of
those reports inside of kaido as I'm
going along um I think I can utilize AI
for portions of the report um and try to
do that a little bit better um but at
the end of the day I think I need to
just write better impact statements and
spend more time on that on that section
uh and rely Less on on the PC videos
that I do because I do kickass PC videos
I really do and I build really really
good excuse me I do really really good
poc's honestly um but the quality of the
explanation isn't quite there I think
I'm jumping over steps and uh it's
making it a little harder for the triers
to
reproduce okay um and the last one here
was uh are you happy with what programs
you were working on um I generally like
it uh I think there are some programs
that have changed quality a little bit
this year um but overall I'm pretty good
I'm not going to not going to name any
names right now um but I think
definitely in the future I would like to
uh hack on similar programs to the ones
that I hacked on this
year okay and then the next section of
the performance is uh performance eval
uh or what did I call it the personal
inventory is uh am am I happy with the
current levels of XYZ so the first one
on the list was Automation and for me
I'm really not happy with my current
levels of automation uh I left the Recon
game a long time ago in the automation
game a long time ago because I was
spending too much time coding and uh not
enough time hacking and I think now with
cursor coming back on the scene um and
me starting to realize the value of
having actual passive automation um I
think I would like to fix that so I may
get back into the Recon game this year
I'm not 100% sold on that but what I am
sold on is I will be doing some lead
generation automation which is going to
be uh mostly Javascript file monitoring
change log monitoring source code
monitoring that sort of thing 100% that
will get done this
year um organization am I happy with my
current levels of organization um I'm
pretty pleased with this actually kaido
really helps with this with the
collections and um being able to sort
stuff out much easier um and with the
new notes plugin I'm I'm sorry I'm sorry
guys just download the free freaking
notes plugin man it's so good um just
having that inside kaido really made it
easy and seamless for me to jump into my
notes take take notes see them
beautified you know on the right hand
side rendered and marked down um so that
really helps a lot and then I've had
this system for a couple years where I
just have like a bugn folder and then I
go into that folder create a another
folder for the Target that I'm working
on and then I have this bash Alias
called temp home which essentially takes
the current uh directory that I'm in and
makes it my temporary like home
directory so whenever I open up my shell
it will take me directly to that
directory um and so I don't like
accidentally put files in a different
folder or something like that uh and
that keeps everything sort of isolated
into uh the project that I'm working on
and then whenever I'm done I have this
Alias rev home which is like revert home
and that takes my my home uh back to you
know where it was
before um so overall pretty pleased with
that um am I pleased with my current
levels of
collaboration um yeah I think
I am okay with it I'm not collaborating
as much as many hackers are and I've
kind of wondered whether that is a a
downside or not um but I think I'm I'm
mostly okay with it um I've definitely
helped a lot of um people this year get
bounties um and I my mentes my two
mentes have done really well um so I'm
pleased with that and I think the times
that I have collaborated with other high
skill hackers have been really rewarding
uh so I think if I can keep it the
collab cation levels at a similar amount
I think that would be good um am I
pleased with the current levels of uh
time that I'm getting to put into bug
Bounty absolutely freaking not okay um
yeah my year got crushed by by critical
thinking and by uh just other stuff
going on in my life um and I really
really did not get to hack much this
year so I am really trying to protect my
time next year uh with this full-time
Buck bounty hunters Guild and with some
accountability saying hey I actually
didn't hack this week what the heck is
going on let's diagnose that um you know
let trying to be really intentional
about building my life around my work
hours involving hacking um you know at
least 80% of the time that's what I'm
shooting for uh 80% of my working hours
I want to be hands on the keyboard
hacking um so that's kind of what I'm
going for okay last but not least
motivation that is the plus side of not
getting to do as much hacking as you
wanted to do is uh when you finally do
get to hacking you are just pumped for
it um so I am like chomping at the bit
to do some hacking which uh after I
record this episode for the rest of
December I'm going to be ready to roll
um hacking on stuff uh when I'm not
spending time with family so um very
excited for that uh but my motivation
overall is great uh and I think as far
as a a a plan goes for that I think I
need to if my if my energy levels kind
of go down um and my motivation for
hacking goes down then I need to um take
some breaks and do some self-care and
then that should come back up or like
I've been doing in the past focus on
other things like critical thinking
building that business my real estate
portfolio um Fitness those sort of
things and then when I come back to
hacking I should be more motivate
motivated um okay so what is my overall
goal for bug Bounty um I put this one
down I might move this one up for youall
on the actual template if you guys want
to follow along yourselves but for me um
my goal for bug Bounty as a full-time
Hunter is to sustain my my life you know
is to meet meet my goals financially um
I have a pretty aggressive uh fire goal
Financial Independence retire early goal
um so I'm going to try to stay on T on
on track for that but at the end of the
day for me as well it's finding cool
[__] that I'm proud of and excited by
because I'm very passionate about web
security and uh whenever I you know am
not finding bugs on a regular basis I
can feel that drain a little bit so I
also want to find inct cool [__] um
yeah that's kind of where I want to be
and I want to make sure I'm I'm growing
as a hacker as well um okay uh what are
my weaknesses as a hacker and how should
we remediate these um yeah for me I
need I need to focus
on focusing less which I think is a
little bit of a weird a weird thing to
say um in the past I have really needed
to kind of get in the zone and like tune
out the world forget about everything
around me including you know any other
responsibilities that I have and just
hack and I think that is not that's a
young man's game and I think I am while
I am only 28 still in my 20s uh I do
have a family I do have a business I do
have employees I have other
responsibilities um so I think I need to
learn more how to hack in the in between
times um uh and I think that's going to
be a challenge for me but I've seen
people do it effectively so I know I can
do it too um
I need to go for bigger attack scenarios
as we saw earlier my high to crit ratio
is really skilled slanted towards highs
and I really need to kind of move that
more into the crit Arena um so I think I
need to try to in remove those
Inhibitors and really push for the crit
um I think I would like to do some
things on different attack surfaces uh
definitely would like to go into the
binary exploitation realm I'm not sure
if that's if 2025 is the year for that I
suppose we'll see um but definitely uh
would like to do uh some different
attack scenarios I think that's been
really rewarding and then also I'd like
to do more automation so those are kind
of the areas where I feel weak as a
hacker I kind of have a limited um
attack surface that I go after with web
and sometimes mobile um and I I don't
have as much Automation in place as I
would like right now okay what are my
strengths as a
hacker um my strengths I'm very thorough
I have a really good understanding of
both client side and server side web
stuff and I am getting a little bit more
into crypto off stuff um and I think
those are some pretty solid strengths um
so that's kind of where the personal
inventory at is at and I'm going to go
through this next section which is my
plan for how to crush it in 2025 um my
goals okay um so the first question on
that that part of the template which
once again you can find on the the blog
the critical thinking blog um is what
areas if any would I like to grow as a
hacker like I mentioned before I would
definitely like to do BU binary
exploitation U I'm going to try to do
one at least one binary exploitation bug
against a bug Bounty program in 2025 I
just do not have experience with those
uh lower level vulnerabilities um and
I'm really fascinated by them and I
think I would respect myself a lot more
as a hacker if I had that in my pocket
as well um and uh as far as other growth
I think I would like to go for more
critical scenarios um who would I like
to collaborate with there are so many
people I would like to collaborate with
I'm not even going to try to name them
um how many hours per week on average
would you like to hack um I'm thinking
25 to 35 hours per week ideally 32 hours
everything else should probably fit into
one square business day um critical
thinking included so we'll see that has
definitely not been the case in the past
two years but um thanks to you guys we'
actually been able to get some staff uh
to help uh on the team uh and we're
finally building out a really good team
here um so hopefully those hours will go
back down in uh in in 2025 uh so and I
can spend more time hacking um How Will
I manage my hacker motivation in 2025
that hasn't really been a problem for me
but I think this full-time bug bounty
hunters Guild is really going to help
how much money would I like to make for
me that's probably around probably going
to bleep bleep that um but you know I
think it's good to set aggressive goals
um how many bugs would I like to submit
I think I'd like to somewhere between
150 and 200 next year I think that'll
give me a good growth rate uh and I
think with some automation that should
totally be possible what would I like my
severity distribution to be um I
definitely like to move a little bit
more towards the the crits maybe take a
little bit off of the some percentages
off the medium and move them into the
crit Arena and some off the highs as
well probably
um uh I'm going to leave off what
programs or platforms because I don't
feel like looking up uh all of the what
if it's a private program or not um what
automation would I like to work on um
for me I've got some really cool stuff
uh in the works for the critical
thinkers that I'm going to release uh I
think 2024 calendar year so by the time
this is out it's probably already going
to be out um but if not pinging me and
be like Justin where's that stuff that
you
forgot um so we'll see we'll see uh but
it's going to be mostly around lead
generation stuff um and yeah definitely
want to do some AI automation as well um
what research would you like to do if
any for me I'd like to do some post
message stuff and then obviously I want
to work with the research team as well
that I mentioned
cb.
C
RL crtical research lab gez could not
get that out critical research lab crl
um if you want to learn more about that
um but yeah I'd like to work with the
guys on in the lab and kind of help them
flesh out their research ideas um for me
besides some post message ideas I don't
have a bunch of research ideas kind of
banging around in my head uh but know
that there are some really awesome
things especially in the client side
that a couple of the guys that I'm
working with um have so excited to try
to flush those out okay and the last
question is what if anything would you
like to contribute to the community
guys this this pod is what I'm
contributing to the community and it is
about everything I can possibly manage
um so I hope you guys enjoyed it um this
has been my my goals for 2025 and my
personal review you guys can find this
on the blog um I think it'd be for you
guys to go down and kind of check that
out and uh do a personal inventory and
set some goals um I guess you guys know
yourself the best though so if that
doesn't work for you then you know maybe
it's more chill than that um I just know
so many of you guys out there are like
really intense goal based people like I
am um so I hope this will be helpful all
right guys uh this is past Justin
signing off from 2024 it's been a great
year thank you so much for listening to
critical thinking bug buny podcast so
appreciate the support and I'm excited
for 2025 we got a lot of fun stuff in
store all right peace and that's a wrap
on this episode of critical thinking
thanks so much for listening and if you
want more critical thinking content head
over to ctbb Dosh show/ Discord join the
Discord there's lots of great
conversations and chats going on over
there and if you want to support the
show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there